wabash.edu 2017-07-09

# Wabash College: Privacy Statement for www.wabash.edu Crawfordsville, Indiana

**WABASH’S COMMITMENT TO PRIVACY**

Wabash College has created this privacy statement to demonstrate our firm commitment to the privacy of our website users. This Privacy Policy outlines the types of personal information received, collected, and used by Wabash College through its web sites and online partners.

The College adheres to legal requirements prescribed by relevant statutes, such as the (FERPA) Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974. Our FERPA document notice may be found at [www.wabash.edu/aboutwabash/info](http://www.wabash.edu/aboutwabash/info).

**1) Information We Collect from Visitors to Our Website**

**Personally Identifiable Information**

Personally Identifiable Information (PII) is information that can be used to identify, contact, or locate an individual, either alone or combined with other information. Such data could include your name, email address, phone number, credit card number, or any other information that is not otherwise publicly available. The information Wabash collects from you is information that you supply to us for purposes such as making a donation, completing a purchase, or requesting admissions information.

**Aggregate Data**

Like other web sites, Wabash makes use of log or session files. This is information automatically collected from you each time you visit our site. Log files typically include your IP address, type of browser, Internet Service Provider, date and time stamp, pages from which you exit our site, and number of clicks.

**Public Forums**

Visitors who use the comment features on our blog sites should understand that Personally Identifiable Information submitted can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. Wabash is not responsible for the information you choose to submit in these forums.

**2) How We Use Information Collected on Our Website**

Personally Identifiable Information and/or aggregate data collected by Wabash College may be used for the following:

Administration of the site;

Development of usage statistics and analysis of trends;

Recruitment of prospective students and their families;

Solicitation of philanthropic gifts to the College; and

Research purposes, including gathering of demographic information.

In addition, names, mailing addresses, and email addresses, and phone numbers provided by visitors through online forms could be added to the College’s database for the purposes of communication and correspondence.

**3) Cookies**

Cookies are small pieces of data automatically stored in a user’s browser when a website is visited. Wabash occasionally places cookies on a visitor’s computer to store information about their preferences, record user-specific information on pages accessed or visited, customize web page content based on browser type or device, or to present visitors with promotional materials on other websites they might visit. Users can set their browsers to receive notification when a web site sends them a cookie so they may accept or reject it. Note that the rejection of cookies may disable some parts of Wabash’s website.

**Third-Party Use of Cookies**

Wabash may place coding on web pages that allows a partner organization or agency to insert a cookie into a visitor’s browser. These are used for the purposes of presenting a visitor with promotional material about Wabash after visitors leave [www.wabash.edu](http://www.wabash.edu/). A partner may also receive your IP address in order to deliver content about Wabash and/or collect aggregate data about the effectiveness of promotional materials.

Users may control third-party cookies via their web browser preference settings. Users may also opt out of the use of third-party cookies, in general, by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) at http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp.

**4) Disclosure of Personal Data to Wabash’s Partners**

Wabash partners with other organizations and agencies to process information or financial transactions. Before it provides personal information to a partner, Wabash will obtain a non-disclosure and confidentiality agreement from its partners. Aggregate data and/or information that is publicly available is not subject to such agreements. Wabash will disclose personal information when required by law, judicial process, warrant, or subpoena.

**5) Wabash’s Commitment to Data Security**

To restrict unauthorized access and to ensure data integrity and security, Wabash’s Information Technology Services implements physical, electronic, and administrative policies and procedures intended to safeguard information the College collects and/or stores. However, the College cannot assure or warrant absolute data security.

**6) Links to External Sites**

This site contains links to external sites as well as sites that are not considered official web pages of Wabash College. This may include personal homepages of students, faculty, and staff containing the URL http://persweb.wabash.edu. Wabash College is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites. Links to these sites are provided as a courtesy and do not imply an endorsement by Wabash College of the site. When notified of sites within the Wabash domain that may violate privacy or copyright practices, Wabash College will make every reasonable effort to bring the site into compliance or remove it from our servers. For more information on our copyright practices, go to: <http://www.wabash.edu/copyright/docs/Policy%20statement%2001_09a.pdf>.

**7) Children’s Privacy**

Wabash does not deliberately collect, or attempt to collect, personal information from children under high school age. However, Wabash cannot always determine if a visitor is a child. In general, Wabash publishes content on its website suitable for and directed to high school students

**8) Your Consent and How to Contact Us**

By visiting the Wabash College website, you consent to the collection, storage, and dissemination of personal information and aggregate data as described above. We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time.

If you have any questions regarding our Privacy Policy, please contact the Communications and Marketing Office at [communications@wabash.edu](mailto:communications@wabash.edu) or by calling (765) 361-6100.

**Choice/Opt-Out**

This site gives users the following options for removing their information from our database, to not receive future communications, or to no longer subscribe to electronic services. This site also gives users the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided.

**Alumni**

  1. You can send email to [alumni@wabash.edu](mailto:alumni@wabash.edu)
  2. You can send mail to the following postal address:

_Alumni Affairs Office, PO Box 352, Crawfordsville, IN 47933_

  1. You can call the following telephone number: 765.361.6369

**Prospective Students**

  1. You can send email to [admissions@wabash.edu](mailto:admissions@wabash.edu)
  2. You can send mail to the following postal address:

_Admissions Office, PO Box 352, Crawfordsville, IN 47933_

  1. You can call the following telephone number: 765.361.6225

**Donors (if not alumni)**

  1. You can send email to [advancement@wabash.edu](mailto:advancement@wabash.edu)
  2. You can send mail to the following postal address:

_Advancement Office, PO Box 352, Crawfordsville, IN 47933_

  1. You can call the following telephone number: 765.361.6360

**_The effective date of this updated privacy policy was May 1, 2016._**
